Guide to the United Hatters, Cap, and Millinery Workers International Union Records TAM.054
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series VI: Danbury Hatters' Case, 1905-1922
  - United States Circuit Court of Appeals, 2nd Circuit: Lawlor v. Loewe, Brief for Defendant in Support of the Demurrer, undated (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - United States Circuit Court of Appeals, 2nd Circuit: Lawlor v. Loewe-Brief for Defendant in Error, 1914 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - United States Supreme Court, no. 900: Lawlor v. Loewe (vol. 3), 1913 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - United States Supreme Court, no. 900: Lawlor v. Loewe-Brief for Plaintiff in Error, 1914 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - United States Supreme Court, no. 900: Lawlor v. Loewe-Brief for Defendant in Error, 1914 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Court of Appeals, District of Columbia: Gompers, Mitchell and Morrison v. United States, 1913 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Supreme Court of Errors, 3rd District, New Haven County: Lawlor v. C.H. Merritt and Son, 1906 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - United States Circuit Court of Appeals, 2nd Circuit: Loewe v. Savings Bank of Danbury, 1903 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Appellate Court of IL, 1st District: Abstract of Record-Eiger v. United Hatters of North America, Locals 22 and 5, undated (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Circuit Cort of the United States, NJ District:Rule to Show Cause, Bill of Complaint, etc.-Samuel Mundheim Company v. John A. Moffitt, undated (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Bills of Prices Signed by Various Hat Manufacturers, 1913-1918 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Records, 1917 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Ledger and Reciepts (1915-1916), Special Assessment on Traveling Cards (1915-1920) (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Memorandum, War Labor Board: in Matter of Danbury Hat Strike, 1918 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Appendices to Memorandum for United States Hat Company, 1915-1916 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Statement of Mr. Hanna, City Clerk of Danbury on position of Hat Manufacturers, undated (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Report of Commissioner McWade of United States Department of Labor, Aug 8, 1917 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - United States Department of Labor Commissioner E.E. Greenwalt's Report, Apr 27, 1918 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Report of United Hatters Position on Strike for National War Labor Board, 1918 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Clippings from Danbury News on Strike, Sep 13, 1917-Oct 23, 1917 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Answers to Mr. Wells' Argument, undated (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Statement of Cuff Hat Company of Danbury, 1918 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Petition to Manufacturers of Danbury, Signed by Danbury Businessmen (published in Danbury News), undated (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Exhibit on Arbitration Agreement of 1910, Jul 24, 1917 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Historical Material on Danbury Case (collected by Charles H. Green), undated (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Historical Material on Danbury Case (collected by Charles H. Green), undated (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Court Order to Attach Homes of Workers in Danbury Case, undated (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Minute Book, Bethel Hat Finishers Local, 1896-1920 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of Conference Between Hat Manufacturers and United Hatters, Dec 1909 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Checkbook, United Hatters, 1917 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Releases of Union from Claims of it's Members, undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Property Records of Danbury Hatters, undated (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Hat Manufacturers Employers Association: Fur Hat Manufacturers-Mutual Protection, 1903 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Hat Manufacturers Employers Association: Agreement Between Local 16 and Young Hat Company, 1919 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Hat Manufacturers Employers Association: Reply of United Hatters of North America to Association of Felt Hat Manufacturers, 1909 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Hat Manufacturers Employers Association: Association of Hat Manufacturers v. Baird Unteidt, undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Hat Manufacturers Employers Association: Charge of Judge Wheeler against Local 10, United Hatters, 1912 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Hat Manufacturers Employers Association: Constitution and By-Laws of Fur Hat Manufacturers Association of Danbury and Bethel, 1903 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Financial Materials, undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
- Series VII: United Hatters, Cap, and Millinery Workers International Union, 1934-1954
  - Proceedings of Convention of Men's Hat Department (vol. 1), 1936 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Proceedings of Convention of Men's Hat Department (vol. 2), 1936 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Constitution on Men's Hat Department, 1935 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Record of Factories Using Union Label, 1936-1941 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Record of Labels Issued, 1939-1951 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Report of Edward Wagenfeld: "Business Mortality of the Millinery Industry", 1942 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Beethoven Hall Property (Headgear Lyceum), undated (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - True Facts About the Injunction Case Against the Men's Hat Department (pamphlet), undated (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Record of Hat Makers' Traveling Cards, 1936-1937 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - The Norwalk Case proposed by Hat Corporation of America (booklet), 1954 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Arbitration Proceedings: Mallory Hat Company v. Locals 10, 11 and 12, Oct 1939-Nov 1940 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Code Authority of the Millinery Industry(booklet), Jan 1935 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Meetings of Special Commission for the Cap and Hat Industry, transcript, Oct 10, 1934-Oct 11, 1934 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Minutes: Proceedings of Chicago Meeting of the Special Commission, Oct 13, 1934 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Audit of Books and Records of the Code Authority of the Millinery Industry, Apr 17, 1934 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Proposed Budget for Code Authority of the Millinery Industry, 1934-1935 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Minutes: General Executive Board and Board of Directors, 1934-1947 (Film R-7436, Reel 1)
  - Minutes: General Executive Board and Board of Directors, 1948-1976 (Film R-7436, Reel 2)
- Series VIII: Charles H. Green Collection, 1827-1944
  - The Headwear Workers, a century of trade unionism: notes, documents and printed materials (part 1), undated (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - The Headwear Workers, a century of trade unionism: notes, documents and printed materials (part 2), undated (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Indenture and Contribution (Dues) Book of Harry Evans, English Hatter, 1908, 1924 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - History-Historical Studies (unfinished), undated (Box 47, Folder 4)
- Series IX: Scrapbooks, 1886-1932
  - Hatters Unions Scrapbook: Minutes, Executive Board Meetings, International Association of Hat Finishers of North America, 1886-1893 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - UHNA Scrapbook: Petty Cash Register, 1920-1927 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - UHNA Scrapbook: Petty Cash Register, 1927-1936 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - UHNA Scrapbook: Register of Apprentices, 1903-1914 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - UHNA Scrapbook: Roll book: Finishers and Makers, A-M, 1907-1916 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - UHNA Scrapbook: Roll book: Finishers and makers, N-Z, 1907-1916 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - UHNA Scrapbook: Roll book: Finishers, 1916-1932 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - UHNA Scrapbook: Roll book: Makers, 1916-1930 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - UHNA Scrapbook: Roll book: Makers, 1923-1936 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - UHNA Scrapbook: Roll book: Makers and Finishers, 1896-1908 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - UHNA Scrapbook: Register of Apprentices, 1914-1939 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - UHNA Scrapbook: Roll book: Operators and Trimmers, 1914-1939 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - UHNA Scrapbook: Roll book: Wool Hatters, 1918-1936 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - UHNA Scrapbook: Straw Hatters, 1917-1935 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - UHNA Scrapbook: Hat Finishers, 1917-1937 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - UHNA Scrapbook: Record of Strike Benefits, 1913-1932 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - UHNA Scrapbook: World War I: Labor News, undated (Box 61, Folder 1)
- Series X: Photographs, 1929-1953
  - Group Portraits, undated (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Group Portraits (Oversize), undated (Box Shared Tamiment OS008, Folder 1)
  - McDonald, Jonn: Testimonial (Letters), 1953 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - McDonald, Jonn: Testimonial (Photocopy), 1953 (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - McDonald, Jonn: Testimonial (Photographs), 1953 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Mil-Kut Social Club Seal (Artifact), 1929 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Portraits, undated (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Souvenir Album, 1934 (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Union Label Placard, undated (Box 72, Folder 9)
- Series XI: Addendum (Unprocessed), 1876-1978
  - Proceedings and Reports of Board of Directors, Convention of Working Men and Capmakers Journal in Hebrew, 1876-1930 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Proceedings of Special Amalgamation Convention of UHNA, 1919-1978 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - UHNA Management Committee's Folder (minutes, reports, correspondence), 1926 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Board Meetings Minutes, 1953-1964 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, Financial Statements, 1959-1969 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - UHNA annual convention addresses, Books and Publications (directories, glossaries, How to Make Hat?, etc.), Financial Documents, 1905-1970 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - UHNA amalgamation files, 1933-1934 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks of UHNA Biennale Conventions, Minutes of Meetings, 1906-1913, 1953 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Merrimac Hat Company, Inc.: Annual Reports, Clippings, Accounting Reports, 1959-1969 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Merrimac Hat Company, Inc.: Correspondence, Cash Receipts, 1959-1960 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Merrimac Hat Company, Inc.: Accounting and Business Operations, 1959 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Merrimac Hat Company, Inc.: Clippings, Miscellaneous, 1959-1963 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Merrimac Hat Company, Inc.: Legal, Minutes, 1959-1962 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Merrimac Hat Company, Inc.: Miscellaneous Correspondence (memos, etc.), 1959-1962 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Merrimac Hat Company, Inc.: Closing Statement, Financial and Legal Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Merrimac Hat Company, Inc.: Clippings, Annual Reports, a survey Manuscript, 1960-1972 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Merrimac Hat Company, Inc.: Correspondence, 1969-1973 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Merrimac Hat Company, Inc.: Important Legal and Financial Correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Merrimac Hat Company, Inc.: Important Legal and Financial Correspondence, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Merrimac Hat Company, Inc.: Important Legal and Financial Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Merrimac Price List, 1963-1964 (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - Merrimac: Import Statistics, 1961-1968 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Merrimac Hat Company, Inc.: Important Legal and Financial Correspondence, 1961 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Merrimac Hat Company, Inc.: Important Legal and Financial Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Merrimack: Import Statistics, 1960-1961 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Merrimac Hat Company, Inc.: Accounting Reports, Financial Reports, 1965-1969 (Box 71, Folder 1)